
<chapter id="anyframeiamadmin_usage">
  <title>Overview of How to Use IAM Admin</title>

  <para>IAM Admin is generally structured with following five menus.</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_user_management">User
      Management</link> : User and usergroup management menu</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_roles_management">Roles
      Management</link> : ROLE management menu. Resources or user, usergroup
      can be registered to a role.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link
      linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_resource_management">Resource
      Management</link> : Resource management menu. Register new resources or
      delete or can set screen control function.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link
      linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_restriction_management">Restriction
      Management</link> : Menu to manage limits by time. Time limitation for
      user, role and resource can be managed.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_system_management">System
      Management</link> : Enterprise application management menu. Provides
      functions of reload and resource information gathering to apply changes
      from IAM Admin.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <section id="anyframeiamadmin_usage_user_management">
    <title>User Management</title>

    <para>User Management menu provides overall management menu for users and
    groups. Click on User List category displays a screen similar to
    the following. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_usermanagement_01_en.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>The menus on left of the screen shows the user group hierarchy
    structure. Use top button to use fold or unfold functions. And create,
    modify and delete group functions are available by right click on the
    tree UI. Click on the group allows to check or modify detail information on
    the group menu of tab menu on the right.</para>

    <para>User list can be checked from Users tab. When a specific group was
    selected from the left group menu, the users belonging to the group are
    displayed. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_usermanagement_02_en.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>Double clicking on an user from the user list moves to user detail
    page. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_usermanagement_03_en.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>User information can be modified from the detail page. A specific
    role to an user can be registered or deleted from bottom ROLE LIST screen.
    Register or delete a role can be done from <link
    linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_roles_management">Roles
    Management.</link></para>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiamadmin_usage_roles_management">
    <title>Roles Management</title>

    <para>Roles Management menu manages roles to be registered to an user or
    resource. Click on the Role List menu displays the tree menu
    showing hierarchy structure similar as user group menu. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_rolesmanagement_01.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>Roles Management menu has 4 tab menus of Role, Resource List, User
    Group and Users. Each menu is a screen displaying the registered
    resources, groups or users when a specific role was selected from the role
    tree on the left.</para>

    <para>Resource List page displays the list of resources allocated to the
    role selected from the left. One cautious thing for allocating a resource
    to a role is role hierarchy structure. When a resource is allocated to a
    sub-role, higher role potentially includes the resources of sub-role. So,
    the higher role has the access authorization for sub-role resources
    without registering the resources separately.</para>

    <para>You can select to display only the resources allocated to current
    role or all resources allocated to sub-role on the select box on top of
    resource list screen. (This menu is allowed only to the user using Oracle
    DB) The following screen is the searched result of all resources
    allocated to sub-role. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_rolesmanagement_02.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>Next menu is User Group tab menu. Selecting the User Group tab menu
    displays the following screen. This screen performs function of allocating
    specific roles to all users belonging to the group to improve trouble of
    registering roles to users individually. The groups in left Multi-select
    box are the list of groups allocated with roles selected from left role
    menu. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_rolesmanagement_03_en.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject> <warning>
        <title>Advice</title>

        <para>Be careful as both of the role and user group have hierarchy
        relation and can cause confusion. As described in role menu, access to
        resources registered to sub-role is allowed to higher role user. But
        don't forget that user group does not operate identically. The higher
        group does not necessarily has access authority of sub-group in user
        group menu. The role for the resources must be allocated in order for
        higher group to have access authority. Make sure to not to use with confusion this function
        with hierarchy structure of role menu.</para>
      </warning></para>

    <para>Click on Users tab menu displays the following 2 lists. Left menu is
    the user list having no allocated roles and the right menu is the user
    list allocated with selected roles. <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="center"
                     fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_rolesmanagement_04_en.jpg" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject></para>

    <para>This menu registers individual user roles, which operates separately
    with previously described role-group allocation. For example, when ROLE_A
    is allocated to the GROUP_A where a specific user USER_A belongs to and a
    different ROLE_B is allocated to the USER_A, the USER_A has access
    authority for resources of both ROLE_A and ROLE_B. So, when allocating a
    role to an user or user group, be careful for overlapping resource
    allocation.</para>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiamadmin_usage_resource_management">
    <title>Resource Management</title>

    <para>Resource Management menu provides a menu to control access to
    controlling resources. Resource Management menu has 3 detail menus of
    Resource List, View List and View Mapping.</para>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_resource_management_sec001">
      <title>Resource List</title>

      <para>Let's take a look at Resource List menu first. List of currently
      registered resources can be checked from Resource List menu. URL, Method
      and PointCut are the 3 types of resource types and registered with each
      special pattern form. URL resource can be registered as regular expression and
      POINT CUT can be registered by using the pattern supported from AspectJ. Method type
      resource is not supporting a specific pattern at the moment. Using the
      patterns other than regular expression, Method resource pattern application and
      others are planned to be reviewed on upcoming version.</para>

      <para>Below screen is the resource list displayed when the Resource List
      is selected. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_01_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Detail screen for the resource can be checked by double clicking
      the specific resource. The detail page can enter below resource name, pattern,
      detail, priority and others. The priority here means the prior matching
      comparison order between overlapping registered resource patterns.
      Meaning that matching with higher priority resource first and giving
      authority. <para>For example, granting priority of 5 to product/*.do,
      URL resource type, and 11 to product/add.do, 12 to product/getProduct.do
      and 13 to product/updateProduct.do resources. The user is planning to
      grant CRUD (create, read, update, delete) authority of the product to
      administrator and grant create, read and update authority, but no
      delete authority to general users. So, the user allocated product/*.do
      resource to ROLE_ADMIN and product/add.do, product/getProduct.do and
      product/updateProduct.do resources to ROLE_USER. But when resources were
      allocated as this can cause the following issues. First, the user
      allocated as administrator will be able to use all CRUD functions
      without limits. But, when a general user calls product/getProduct.do URL
      resource, the product/getProduct.do resource will be compared by
      matching with resource patterns with priority as the base. So, the
      product/*.do pattern with higher priority will be matching priorily to
      compare product/*.do resource allocated ROLE_ADMIN authority and the
      authority of current user. In the result, the general user access to
      product/getProduct.do request will be denied as the user does not have
      ROLE_ADMIN authority,</para> <para>The followings must be complied in
      order to not to have errors as above. <warning>
          <title>Advice</title>

          <para>
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Give priority to general resources (ex. *.do) as low as
                possible (register with larger number).</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Setting priority higher to frequently referred resources
                will improve performance.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>For the resources unnecessary to be registered as
                secured resources, register the corresponding pattern in
                intercept-url of http namespace tag in Spring Security's
                default set up file as filters="none".</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </warning></para> <para>The following figure is the detail information
      screen by double clicking a specific resource. You can see that auto
      complete function is being used when registering resource patterns.
      <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_02.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para> The user basically needs to write resource
      pattern fields. Auto complete function is supported on resource pattern
      entry for convenience and prevent mistakes. When the pattern was
      registered with auto complete function, using regular type and others to
      register similar name resources in a bundle is not allowed. In such
      case, clicking the direct entry check box of detail resource pattern
      field will allow the user to register resource directly. In this case,
      it is recommended to not to use this method unless the user is a expert
      on pattern regular expression type as there is a possibility of application
      malfunction by user mistakes.</para>

      <para>Below figure is a screen you can see when you are entering URL
      type resource patterns. URL pattern is composed with URL Request addess
      on the left and parameters on the right. You can use parameters
      selectively as they are not mandatory. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_03.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Below 3 figures are screens when entering Method type resource
      patterns. Method pattern has total of 3 input field and they are
      package, class and method entry fields from left. As the <link
      linkend="anyframeiamadmin_usage_system_management">System
      Management</link> menu's <link
      linkend="anyframeiam_usage_system_management_sec002">Resource
      Gathering</link> gathers and saves enterprise application resources, the
      patterns can be entered easily by using auto complete function on
      entering patterns. Writing orders of package information, class and
      method from the left expresses 3 entries combines form in below detail
      resource pattern category. The combined information is the pattern form
      to be saved finally. <para>Enter package first. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_04.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para> <para>Enter class next. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_05.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para> <para>And enter method for last. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_06.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para> If you cannot remember resource name, enter a
      space and all resource lists will be displayed. Enter resource patterns
      with this result will be much easier.</para>

      <para>Lastly, let's take a look at entering the POINTCUT type resources.
      POINTCUT pattern has only one input field and when the user uses auto
      complete function to write entry field, the below detail resource
      pattern field completes it to AspectJ support pattern type. If you are
      an expert on AspectJ supported PointCut type pattern, you can click the
      Self Input check box and enter detail resource pattern field directly to
      register numerous patterns as a bundle. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_07.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject> <para>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata align="center"
                         fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_08.jpg" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </para></para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_resource_management_sec002">
      <title>View List</title>

      <para>View List menu offers functions to register and modify/delete View
      Resource for screen control according to the authorization. To control
      the screen according to authority, use iam:access tag as the
      followings on the page to surround the contents to control.
      <programlisting language="xml">
<![CDATA[<iam:access hasPermission="${iam:getPermissionMask(\"CREATE\")}" viewResourceId="listCategory">
	<td><input type="button" name="addCategory" onClick="javascript:fncAddCategoryView();"></td>
</iam:access>]]></programlisting>
The screen to register, modify and delete
      the resources corresponding with viewResourceId in the tag is the View
      List menu.</para>

      <para>Below screen is an example of View List page. Double clicking on a
      specific View resource allows to move to detail sccreen. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_09_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Next is a View resource detail information page. The user needs to
      enter View Resource ID directly and must pass overlap verification in
      order to save successfully. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_10_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_resource_management_sec003">
      <title>View Mapping</title>

      <para>View Mapping menu manages the View resources entered by the user
      and allocations between user, group and role. Basically, as only the
      user with the Permission assigned within iam:access by administrator has
      the authority for tag contents, easy UI is offered to easily manage the
      Permission from View Mapping screen.</para>

      <para>Selecting the View Mapping menu will display the list of
      users with Permissions to View resources. Reference Type category is
      the category showing whether the Permission is allocated to an
      individual user or group or a role. Note that Permission allocated
      to a user has higher priority than user and user gruop than a role. For
      example, let's assume the View resource authority for modification of
      Update Category was given to 'ROLE_ADMIN' role and 'STAFF' group. SATFF
      group is allocated with 'ROLE_STAFF', lower hierarchy of 'ROLE_ADMIN'.
      So, the users allocated to 'ROLE_STAFF' other than STAFF group has no
      authorities for View resource with Update Category ID, but only the
      STAFF group has authority for the resource. Likewise, even when
      resources are not allocated to the group, the authority for View
      resource can be given to an individual user. As this regulation is
      defined to set exception cases among all the users in a group, it is
      recommended to create a new role and allocate authority to the role for
      situation of necessary to give similar authorities to various users in a
      group.</para>

      <para>Below figure is an exmaple screen of allocation list displayed on
      View Mapping menu selection. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_11.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>The following figure is an example screen of allocating roles,
      groups and users to View resources. Enter the View resource ID to be
      managed on top of the screen and use Add Role, Add Group and
      Add User buttons to give authority to the subject. Default setting
      for Permission list is READ, WRITE, CREATE, DELETE, ADMINISTRATION,
      LIST, PRINT and others as shown on below figure and the user can modify
      with set up file. See the following <link
      linkend="anyframeiamcore_customerconfiguration">Link</link> for user
      setting change. <link
      linkend="anyframeiamcore_customerconfiguration">IAM Core
      Configuration</link> <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_resourcemanagement_12_en.jpg" />
			</imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiamadmin_usage_restriction_management">
    <title>Restriction Management</title>

    <para>Restriction Management offers various menus to manage the resources
    depending by time. Restricted Times List and Times Mapping menus are the
    detail menus.</para>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_restriction_management_sec001">
      <title>Restricted Times List</title>

      <para>Let's take a look at Restricted Times List screen first. Below
      figure is an example screen displayed by clicking Restricted Times List
      menu. This screen can register/modify/delete the date and time of
      resources desired for limitation. Detail categories are Time Type,
      start/end time, start/end date, description and others. Time Type has 5
      categories of improve, daily, weekend, holiday and crash. These mean
      system improvement, everyday, weekends, holidays and error occurrences
      respectively. Pay attention when the weekend of Time Type was selected.
      When set as weekly, users can assume that time control setting can be
      possible for every weekends between start and end time, but <emphasis
      role="bold">IT DOES NOT.</emphasis> The Time Type category is just a
      field saving time resources as a text form for easier classification and
      user must set the start date and end date personally. So, when the
      user has set the start date to 091001 (Oct. 1, 2009) and end date to
      091031 (Oct. 31, 2009) to control authorization for every weekends of
      October, actual is that the authorization will be controlled for whole
      October unlike the user's expectation. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_01_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Double clicking on a specific time from Time List screen will move
      to detail screen. Modification to the time resource from detail screen
      is allowed. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_02_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_restriction_management_sec002">
      <title>Times Mapping</title>

      <para>Next screen is Times Mapping menu. The Times Mapping screen has
      total of 3 tab menus of Time-Role, Time-Resource and
      Time-Exclusion.</para>

      <para>First, let's take a look at Time-Role menu. The Time-Role menu
      restricts users with specific roles for a specific time by allocating
      roles to time resources created from previous Restricted Times List
      screen. Click on Time-Role menu to see below screen. Below list screen
      lists the user configured time and allocated roles one by one. Double
      click on a specific allocation to move to detail screen. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_03_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Below screen is a detail information page showing allocation
      information between time-00001 and ROLE_MANAGER. First, enter the
      desired time restrict ID by finding from Time ID field and double click
      on the restriction desired role from below ROLES LIST will display the
      role list on the right. One thing to be careful here is, if the user has
      set time restriction for a specific role, the roles under the role also
      has time restriction. For example, when time was restricted from 000000
      to 235959 to ROLE_MANAGER role as below figure for error handling
      purpose, the users belonging to ROLE_USER and
      ISAUTHENTICATED_ANONYMOUSLY roles are also restricted from 000000 to
      235959. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_07_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Next, let's take a look at Time-Resource menu. The Time-Resource
      menu is to control access authority to a specific resource for a
      specific time. The list of resources allocated for a specific time can
      be seen. Double click on a specific Time ID displays the detail screen
      page to check resource lilsts allocated to the time and descriptions.
      Below figure is a detail description page of Time-Resource list. To set
      resource restriction by time, select the desired time's Time ID from top
      Time ID field first and click below Add Resource button to check the
      displaying pop-up. Click the desired resource from the pop-up window and
      Add button displays the resource being allocated on detail screen page.
      <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_04_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>The menu to look at for last is Time-Exclusion. This menu can set
      exceptional cases for access restriction depending on time configured
      from Time-Resource menu. In other words, applying exception case by
      opening the system exceptionally to a user with administrator authority
      after blocking access to entire system for error recovery. Click on
      Time-Exclusion menu displays the list as below figure. Double click on a
      specific category to move to a detail list page. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_05_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Below figure is the detail screen page of Time-Exclusion. To give
      exclude condition for time restriction, use the search button on the
      right of top Resource ID field first to check if there is an allocation
      assigned between Time and Resource. Click the search button displays the
      existing Time-Resource allocation list, from this, click the resource
      desired for exclusion. And the following detail categories are completed
      automatically then open below Role Tree and double click on the role
      desired for exclusion displays the corresponding role as a list on the
      right. One thing to be careful here is, the existing roles higher than
      the role set as exclusion by user also gets access restriction
      cancelled. For example, when the ROLE_MANAGER role user is set as
      exclusion from web-000013 resource restriction as below figure, the
      users belonging to ROLE_ADMIN, the higher users of ROLE_MANAGER, also
      get restriction cancellations for web-000013 resource. So, keep in mind
      that the higher roles user of the roles set as exclusion also get
      restriction cancellation when setting exclusions. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_restrictionmanagement_06_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiamadmin_usage_system_management">
    <title>System Management</title>

    <para>System Management menu offers simple control functions for business
    application. System Management menu has 2 sub-menus of Resource Reload and
    Resource Gathering.</para>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_system_management_sec001">
      <title>Resource Reload</title>

      <para>Resource Reload menu offers the functions to apply the settings
      from 4 previously explained menus. Basically, to apply the changes, the
      business application server must restart, but using this function allows
      applying the settings without restarting the server. Click on Resource
      Reload menu displays the following figure screen. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_systemmanagement_01.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>

      <para>Select the target application server and choose to reload the
      information for user/role/resource or reload information of time
      management menu from Select Box, then clicking the below Reload button
      will display completion message after a moment of loading.</para>

      <para>This action must be performed when the target application server
      is in operation. Or the following error messages will display.
      <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_useage_systemmanagement_02_en.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_usage_system_management_sec002">
      <title>Resource Gathering</title>

      <para>Resource Gathering menu offers functions to gather information of
      target application. Using this function gathers target application bean
      setting and Request URL address and others and save temporarily. Saved
      information provides convenience to users to register resources more
      easily through auto complete function when registering resources from
      Resource Managment menu. Click on Resource Gathering menu displays the
      screen as below figure. Select the application server desired for
      resource gathering and click on Reload button will display completion
      message after a moment of loading. <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center"
                       fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iam_useage_systemmanagement_03.jpg" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject></para>
    </sect2>
  </section>
</chapter>
