<chapter id="anyframeiamcore_accesscontrol">
  <title>Access Control</title>

  <para>A DB based permission can be assigned (IAM Admin provides Data
  management) to user define resource (view resource) and IAM Core offers API
  (service) and the tag library using the service to confirm the allowed
  permission by checking if the logged user has arranged permission.</para>

  <para>Just like using in Spring Security ACL, permission by Bit Masking was
  enabled.</para>

  <para>Used as the function to confirm permission for READ, WRITE, CREATE,
  DELETE, ADMINISTATION and others for the screens generally required from SI
  project.</para>

  <para>Use below viewResourceAccessService to check the permission of the
  java codes. (It is recommended to apply AOP to common the permission check
  logic. It will be guided later on)</para>

  <programlisting language="java">
<![CDATA[boolean result = 
		viewResourceAccessService.isGranted(
			"updateCategory", Arrays.asList(new Integer[] { 3 }))]]></programlisting>

  <para>Above bit mask mark 3 is 0..00011 and means READ and WRITE permission.
  To gain the bit mask corresponding to above 3,
  ExtBasePermission.getPermissionMask("READ,WRITE")can be used
  together.</para>

  <para></para>

  <para>Apply to draw HTML for only when the service call function or button
  areas having authority by surrounded with tags as below in jsp
  page.</para>

  <programlisting language="java">
<![CDATA[<%@ taglib uri="/WEB-INF/anyframe-iam.tld" prefix="iam" %>
..
<iam:access hasPermission=
	"${iam:getPermissionMask(\"CREATE\")}" viewResourceId="listCategory">
 function fncAddCategoryView() {
  ..
 }
</iam:access>
..
<iam:access hasPermission=
	"${iam:getPermissionMask(\"CREATE\")}" viewResourceId="listCategory">
  Add Button Area
</iam:access>]]></programlisting>

  <para>Note that the authority was not actually handled even as limited as
  above screen. For security reasons, actual defenses (Web request
  authorization, method authorization, view resource ACL, domain object ACL
  ..) required from the server.</para>
</chapter>
