<chapter id="anyframeiam_overview">
  <title>Anyframe IAM Overview</title>

  <para>Anyframe IAM is Identity and Access Management Framework that provides
  security solution(user authentication and authorization management) for enterprise
  application based on JAVA EE. Enterprise application based on JAVA EE has various
  required item for user authentication and authorization management and developing new
  functions every time for each enterprise application cost lots of additional
  money and resources. As the Anyframe IAM based on Spring Security is a
  framework that provides user authentication and authorization management for enterprise
  application based on Anyframe or spring Framework, it improves developing
  productivity, active for user authentication and authorization management and support
  for developing application of flexible form.</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata align="center" contentdepth="100%"
                 fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_architecture_en.jpg"
                 scalefit="1" width="100%" />
    </imageobject>
  </mediaobject>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_whatissecurity">What is Security
      ?</link></para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_whatisspringsecurity">What is Spring
      Security ?</link></para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_characteristic">Main feature of
      Anyframe IAM</link></para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_whyanyframeiam">Why Anyframe IAM
      ?</link></para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_features">Main function of Anyframe
      IAM</link></para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><link linkend="anyframeiam_referencedoss">See
      opensource</link></para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <section id="anyframeiam_whatissecurity">
    <title>What is Security ?</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Security of IT field means avoiding access to unauthorized
        information asset(system/program/data…) .</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Generally, It includes the two main functions,<emphasis
        role="bold">Authentication</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> and
        Authorization.</emphasis></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiam_whatisspringsecurity">
    <title>What is Spring Security ?</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>As the strong and flexible security solution for enterprise
        application, IAM has strength for an application based on Spring.
        The traditional Servlet specification security has the limited
        security of considering only the setting for each container,
        transference issue and web request, but the Spring Security
        offers service layer and domain object level security. Spring Security is 
        possible to secure under configuration. And its component is very excel at reusing.
        It is verified through many site under various environments and also the
        representative Spring subproject with most active community and fast
        function improvement</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiam_characteristic">
    <title>Main feature of Anyframe IAM</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">IAM Core based on Spring Security
        :</emphasis> IAM Core that control an authentication and authorization
        by installing at enterprise application is written based on Spring
        Security, it is built up based on DB generally. Changing of current
        application can be minimized when applying to application based on
        Anyframe or Spring.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">IAM Admin Console as a Independent application
        :</emphasis> Operation of IAM Core is consisted based on DB data and
        IAM Admin Console is a tool for control a content of DB. It can be
        consisted as independent type from application because It runs
        different from conventional enterprise application.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Succeed to Strong Function of Spring
        Security : </emphasis> Extension and succeed to strong function of
        Spring Security, providing the function of authentication,
        authorization that are flexible and extensible.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiam_whyanyframeiam">
    <title>Why Anyframe IAM ?</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>There is weak point for user,role,secured resource,
        authorization mapping because Spring Security supports only XML based
        configuration(simple setting is possible from 2.0.X through Namespace but
        setting is on XML).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>
        Anyframe IAM apply for making authentication and authorization based on DB.
        It also standardizes/extends function/refines requirement for management. 
        Through this, IAM Framework is implemented with strength of Spring Security and
        ease to use at SI project.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiam_features">
    <title>Main Function of Anyframe IAM</title>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_overview_sec001">
      <title>IAM Core</title>

      <para>Core of Anyframe IAM is based on Spring Security, it is installed
      at business application based on Anyframe or Spring and
      authentication,authorization are added by minimizing a previous work
      code changing. Especially, operating based on extended setting
      information as DB base is different from Spring Security that save a
      configuration information as XML file.
      Anyframe IAM Core has the following feature.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">Service Layer and Access Control of User
            Defined Resource(ACL)</emphasis>
          </para>

          <para>Authorization checking means controlling for web request
          generally. IAM Core based on Spring Security can treat not only
          controlling for web request but security through authorization
          controlling for main object and service layer. And also it provides
          Tag and API related to view resource access that provides permission
          check function for frequently requested screen on the scene. </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">Separation of concerns</emphasis>
          </para>

          <para>Grant a security by using a Servlet Filter, Interception through 
          Java AOP and it works by separating from normal operation
          code section because it works based on Ioc and Lifecycle service of Spring. </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">Configuration based on Database</emphasis>
          </para>

          <para>As IAM Core of Anyframe supports a generally used DB based
          configuration, it is more convenient than XML based configuration and able to
          control a security related configuration with easy and flexible way.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="anyframeiam_overview_sec002">
      <title>IAM Admin</title>

      <para>Anyframe provides a IAM Admin web application to control Database
      setting for operation of IAM Core. IAM Admin is built up based on
      technology of jQuery, SpringMVC, HibernateJPA and others and user who
      have admin authorization can handle and control a DB based secured
      setting through functions provided by UI of IAM Admin. </para>
    </sect2>
  </section>

  <section id="anyframeiam_referencedoss">
    <title>See Open Source</title>

    <para>Main open source that is used at Anyfame IAM is the
    followings</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://www.trirand.com/blog/">jqGrid
        Plugin</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://www.jstree.com/">jsTree Plugin</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://static.springsource.org/spring-security/site/index.html">Spring
        Security</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink
        url="http://spring-json.sourceforge.net/">Spring-Json</ulink></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><ulink url="http://www.hibernate.org/">Hibernate</ulink></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
