<chapter id="anyframeiamadmin_overview">
	<title>Anyframe IAM Admin</title>

	<para>
	    IAM Admin is provided in special web application format that provides console function, 
		and is deployed in WAR format within Web Application Server when IAM Core is installed and set. 
		IAM Admin View section is implemented with jQuery and JSP technology. 
		Controller section consists of Anyframe Web, and Model section consists of HibernateJPA and Anyframe Core.
	</para>

	<para>
	    IAM Core provides functions that control target application authorization based on DB setting. 
		IAM Admin makes it easier for manager to manipulate DB setting that Core relies on, 
		and transfers control signal so that Core can recognize changed contents. 
	</para>

	<figure>
		<title>Anyframe IAM Architecture</title>
		<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" align="center"
			fileref="../image/anyframeiam/iamadmin_architecture.jpg" />
	</figure>

	<para>IAM Admin uses jQuery, which is JavaScript Framework, to control UI. 
		Request and response with server while minimizing view refresh can be done using jQuery. 
		Plugins are provided in jQuery, and among them, jQuery plugins used in Anyframe IAM are as follows. 
		(Explanations on jQuery are not included in the manual scope so refer to the link below.)
	</para>

	<itemizedlist>

		<listitem>
			<para><ulink url="http://www.trirand.com/blog/">jqGrid Plugin</ulink></para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para><ulink url="http://www.jstree.com/">jsTree Plugin</ulink></para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para><ulink
				url="http://bassistance.de/jquery-plugins/jquery-plugin-autocomplete/">jQuery Autocomplete plugin</ulink></para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para><ulink url="http://jqueryui.com/">jQuery UI : DatePicker and some sections</ulink></para>
		</listitem>

	</itemizedlist>

	<section id="anyframeiamadmin_characteristic">
		<title>Anyframe IAM Admin Characteristics</title>
		<para>IAM Admin provides the following characteristics to enhance user convenience and functions 
			by adding functions provided by IAM Core that is based on Spring Security. 
			(Authorization and application information collection developed based on HttpInvoker 
			and is run without being limited by firewall.)
				</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Cross Browser Support</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>IAM Admin supports Cross Browser and is implemented so that it runs in the same way in 
					browsers other than Internet Explorer such as Firefox, Chrome, and Safari.
				</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="60%" scalefit="1" scale="60" align="center" fileref="../image/anyframeiam/browsers.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Target Application Authorization Reload</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					Authorization information changed in IAM Admin is not committed until authorization reload is clearly requested, 
					and target application (generally business application) authorization information is renewed 
					when executing authorization reload function after manager finishes authorization change. 
					</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="60%" scalefit="1" scale="60" align="center" fileref="../image/anyframeiam/auth_reload.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Target Application Information Collection</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					New functions can be added or changed when continuing maintenance of target application. 
					IAM Admin provides function that collects target application information so that 
					protection resource can be easily registered.
					</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata width="60%" scalefit="1" scale="60" align="center"
							fileref="../image/anyframeiam/resource_gathering.jpg" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Time Limit Authorization Management</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					After setting time limit for specific resource or role in IAM Admin, 
					resource access during allowed time and role access can be controlled, 
					and roles that are exceptions to these rules (manager that has access permission, etc.) can be defined.  
					</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Auto Complete Support </emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					It is difficult to register protected resources of target application for authorization management. 
					IAM Admin uses auto complete function to provide hints based on target application information 
					so that user can easily register protected resources. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
			
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Integrated Application Management</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					Multiple applications can be managed through one Admin Console.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Excel Data Import/Export</emphasis>
				</para>
				<para>
					Use Import/Export function of Excel file to easily perform initial data building or current status backup. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiamadmin_services">
		<title>Anyframe IAM Admin Service</title>

		<para>
		    IAM Admin can manage DB-based information through Service. 
			The following diagram and explanations show IAM Admin service. 
			DAO in the below diagram is formed based on Hibernate-JPA. 
			For information on using related services to form authorization, refer to the instructions. 
			</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Core Service #1</title>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" align="center" fileref="../image/anyframeiam/svc_auth_group.jpg" />
		</figure>

		<para>
		    This is the first list of Services that are mainly used in IAM Admin. 
			It manages information that are mainly looked into in IAM Core 
			such as user group-user relationship (groupsUsers), users (users), authorization (authorities), 
			roles (roles), and role-resource relationship (securedResourceRoles).
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Core Service #2</title>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" align="center"
				fileref="../image/anyframeiam/svc_group_candidate.jpg" />
		</figure>

		<para>
            This is the second list of Services mainly used in IAM Admin. 
			It manages information such as user groups (groups), resources (securedResource), 
			and resource candidate (candidateSecuredResources).
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Authorization Control Service based on Time Setting</title>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" align="center" fileref="../image/anyframeiam/svc_restricted.jpg" />
		</figure>

		<para>
		     After setting time limit for specific resource or role in IAM Admin, 
			 resource access during allowed time and role access can be controlled, 
			 and roles that are exceptions to these rules (manager that has access permission, etc.) can be defined. 
			</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Service for View Control</title>
			<imagedata align="center" scalefit="1" width="60%" scale="100" 
				fileref="../image/anyframeiam/svc_viewresource.jpg" />
		</figure>

		<para>When developing business application, there are times when view display is controlled according to the authorization of use, 
		and when menu display has to be controlled. In this case, service to check authorization should be provided. 
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
