<chapter id="anyframeiam_overview">
	<title>Anyframe IAM Overview</title>

	<para>Anyframe IAM is Identity &amp; Access Management Framework that provides
  security solution(user authentication and authorization) for Java EE-based enterprise
  application. Java EE-based enterprise
  application has various requirements for user authentication and authorization and developing new
  functions every time for each enterprise application costs significant amount of financial and other resources. 
  As the Anyframe IAM based on Spring Security is a
  framework that provides user authentication and authorization for enterprise
  application based on Anyframe or spring Framework, it enhances development productivity
  and enables the active management of user authentication and authorization and more flexible application development.
	</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"
				align="center" fileref="../image/anyframeiam_en/iam_architecture_en.jpg" />
		</imageobject>
		<textobject>
			<phrase>
				위 그림은 Anyframe IAM의 기본 구조도이다. Anyframe IAM은 Anyframe 또는 Spring Framework 기반의 엔터프라이즈 어플리케이션에
				설치되어 사용자/그룹/역할/자원/시간별접근 등의 기능을 제공한다.
			</phrase>
		</textobject>
	</mediaobject>

	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_whatissecurity">What is Security ?</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_whatisspringsecurity">What is Spring Security ?</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_characteristic">Functions of Anyframe IAM</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_whyanyframeiam">Why Anyframe IAM ?</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_features">Core functions of Anyframe IAM</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>

		<listitem>
			<para>
				<link linkend="anyframeiam_referencedoss">Reference opensource</link>
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>

	<section id="anyframeiam_whatissecurity">
		<title>What is Security ?</title>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Security of IT domain refers to denying access to unauthorized information asset (system/program/data, etc.)			
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					Generally, It includes two core functions,<emphasis
        role="bold">Authentication</emphasis><emphasis role="bold"> and
        Authorization.</emphasis>					
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiam_whatisspringsecurity">
		<title>What is Spring Security?</title>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					As the strong and flexible security solution for enterprise
        application, IAM has strength for Spring-based application.
        While existing Servlet specification security has the limitation on
        security considering setting by container, transference issue or web request,
        the Spring Security provides service layer and domain object level security. 
        And based on definition-based, flexible security application, it is an opensource security framework
        whose security layer component is highly usable.
        It has been verified through many sites under various environments and is also the
        representative Spring subproject with most active community and fast
        function improvement.      					
				</para>
			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiam_characteristic">
		<title>Functions of Anyframe IAM</title>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Spring Security- based IAM Core:</emphasis>
					IAM Core, which is installed at enterprise application and controls authentication and authorization, is written based on Spring Security
					and built based on DB. If applied to Anyframe or Spring-based application, its impact of existing application modification can be minimized.				
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">IAM Admin Console of Independent format:</emphasis>
					Running IAM Core is based on DB data and IAM Admin Console is a tool to manage the DB contents.
					As it runs separately from existing enterprise application, separate management is also possible.					
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis role="bold">Inheriting strong functions of Spring Security at is is:
					</emphasis>
					Inherited and extended strong functions of Spring Security and provides flexible and extendable authentication and authorization.					
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiam_whyanyframeiam">
		<title>Why Anyframe IAM ?</title>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					As Spring Security supports XML-based setting only(from 2.0.X onwards simple setting is possible through Namespace, but it is xml setting as well.),
					there is a weak point of difficult management such as user, role, secured resources, authorization mapping, etc.					
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					For management through general user control based on Web UI screen by standardization/function extension/refinement 
					of best practice authentication/authorization 
					befitting Korea's SI situation, it was needed to secure flexible and strong IAM framework equipped with strength of Spring Security 
					and practical SI project.
					
					
					<!-- Anyframe IAM has made DB of authorization based on SI situation of Korea.
					In addition, standardization, extension and refinement were made for the requirements of the management function.-->
				</para>
			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiam_features">
		<title>Core functions of Anyframe IAM</title>
		<sect2 id="anyframeiam_overview_sec001">
			<title>IAM Core</title>

			<para>Anyframe IAM is based on Spring Security, and installation into Anyframe
				or Spring-based business application can minimize the modification of existing business code and add authentication and authorization function.
				In particular, in that it runs based on setting information extending from DB, it differs from Spring Security which saves setting information
				in the existing XML way.</para>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Service Layer and User-Defined Access Control List (ACL)</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Generally, authorization check means web request control.
						IAM Core based on Spring Security can not only control web request but also can handle security by
						 checking authorization of service layer and domain object.
						 In addition, it provides view resource access-related Tag and API which provide permission check function on
						  pages with many requests from field.						
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Separation of ROI (Region of Interest)</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Assigns security by using Interception through Servlet Filter,  and as Java AOP and runs based on Ioc and Lifecycle of Spring,
						it runs separately form general ROI.						
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Database-based setting </emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Spring Security which IAM Core is based on controls the security setting through xml-based setting.
						As Anyframe IAM Core supports generally-used DB-based setting, it is more universal than xml
						and can control security-related setting in simple and flexible way.						
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id="anyframeiam_overview_sec002">
			<title>IAM Admin</title>

			<para>Anyframe provieds IAM Admin web application for managing Database setting which IAM Core runs based on.
			IAM Admin was built based on technical components such as jQuery, SpringMVC, HibernateJPA, etc. and authorized users can control DB-based security setting
			through functions provided by UI.
			 </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">RIA-based UI which supports Cross Browser
						</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Provides dynamic UI where page Refresh was minimized by using jQuery,
						and supports Cross Browser environment including Internet Explorer.
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Target application authority reload </emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Can apply authority information to target application by using explicit authority reload function
						and supports authority reload in clustering environment.
					</para>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Target application information collection</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Supports easier resource registration by providing collection function of target application resources.						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Authorization based on time limitation setting</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Can control access by setting time range on specific resources or role, and other exception rules can also be set.						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Easy resource registration through Auto Complete </emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Provides dynamic UI-based guide to users when registering protected resources based on collected resources information of target application.						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold"> Integrated management of application</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Integrated management of multiple applications is possible through one Admin Console.					
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">Excel Data Import/Export</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Can easily build early data backup the current status by using  Import/Export function of Excel file.						
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<!-- listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis role="bold">RIA / X-Internet UI Control</emphasis>
					</para>
					<para>
						Can control whether UI components of TOBESOFT MiPlatform and Adobe Flex should be shown or not.					
					</para>
				</listitem-->
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect2>

	</section>

	<section id="anyframeiam_referencedoss">
		<title>Reference opensouce</title>

		<para>Main opensources used in Anyframe IAM are as the following.
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://www.trirand.com/blog/">jqGrid Plugin</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://www.jstree.com/">jsTree Plugin</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink
						url="http://static.springsource.org/spring-security/site/index.html">Spring Security</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://spring-json.sourceforge.net/">Spring-Json</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://www.hibernate.org/">Hibernate</ulink>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>
